Guide to the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union Photographs and Other Material PHOTOS.151
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Food and Commercial Workers International Union Photographs and Other Material
circa 1938-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Food and Commercial Workers International Union
Retail Clerks International Association. Local 1111
United Food and Commercial Workers International Union. Local 1245
PHOTOS.151
1.5 Linear Feet in 1 oversize flat box, 1 manuscript box and 1 folder.
The United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) was created through the merger of the Amalgamated Meat Cutters Union and the Retail Clerks International Union following its founding convention in June 1979. The collection consists of photographs and other material documenting the activities of two locals, the Retail Clerks International Association, Local 1111 and the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245, that belong to the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) and/or its predecessors, including the Retail Clerks International Association (RCIA).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of photographs and other material documenting the activities of two locals, the Retail Clerks International Association, Local 1111 and the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245, that belong to the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) and/or its predecessors, including the Retail Clerks International Association (RCIA).
Separated Materials
One AFL-CIO-CLC-UFCW button from October 1984 (probably from the United Federation of Food and Commercial Workers Annual Convention), has been removed and placed with the Tamiment/Wagner Button Collection (BUTTONS 001).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Provenance unknown but we have reason to believe that materials in Series I: United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245 were donated by the United Federation of Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245. The accession numbers associated with the collection are 1986.004, NPA.2000.282, NPA.2005.057, and NPA.2007.024.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in three series, as follows:
Series I: United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245
Series II: Retail Clerks International Association, Local 1111
Series III: Oversize Convention Photographs
Historical/Biographical Note
The United Food and Commercial Workers International Union (UFCW) was created through the merger of the Amalgamated Meat Cutters Union and the Retail Clerks International Union following its founding convention in June 1979. William H. Wynn, president of the Retail Clerks International Union and one of the designers of the merger, became president of UFCW at the time of its founding. The merger created the largest union affiliated with the AFL-CIO. In 1983, the UFCW held its first regular convention in Montreal, Quebec, Canada. In 1984 and 1985 the UFCW pursued aggressive campaigns and organized 136,000 workers. In 1994 longtime UFCW staff member and organizer Douglas H. Dority was elected the second International Union President following the retirement of Wynn.
Clerks (Retail trade) |x Labor unions.; Food industry and trade |x Employees.; Food industry and trade -- Employees -- Labor unions; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union; Retail Clerks International Association. Local 1111; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union. Local 1245
- United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245
  Scope and Content Note
  Series consists of over 120 black-and-white photographs, 6 color photographs, 14 contact sheets, and 5 strips of 35mm negatives that document the history of the United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245 between circa 1964 to 1986. The photographs include individual and group portraits of union leadership and staff, including Local 1245 president Frank DeVito, UFCW president William H. Wynn, and future UFCW president Doug Dority; event photographs; and documentary-style photographs taken for Local 1245's newsletter, 1245 News. Also includes a small amount of printed materials, including press releases, legal documents, clippings and ephemera.
  Historical/Biographical Note
  The United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, Local 1245 is based in Northern New Jersey and represents workers in the supermarket industry and other smaller industries. During the 1960s and 1970s the union, formerly the Retail Clerks International Association Local 1245 (AFL-CIO), was led by president Frank DeVito and membership included supermarket workers in North Jersey, Hockland County, Staten Island, New York City and Long Island.
  - "1245 News Year 1972" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acme Markets Pamphlet, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Business Representative, James McMullen Stops at Stop & Shop #381 in Paramus, N.J., undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Charge Against Local 1245 Retail Clerks Union, Feb 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Feb 1964-Apr 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Constitution Committee, Aug 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Contact Sheets, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - DeVito, Frank, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Frank Devito: Portrait, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Devito, Frank: Speaking, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dority, Doug: Speaking, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Old Pictures for May 1986 Issue of 1245 News", undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Portraits: Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Portraits: Individual, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Press Releases, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Speakers, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - UFCW1245: ACME Markets Affidavit, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - UFCW Annual Convention, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Wagner Archive Exhibit: UFCW 1245 (September 1989), undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Unspecified Events, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Retail Clerks International Association, Local 1111
  The series consists of approximately 150 black-and-white photographs, and related ephemera, that document the history of Retail Clerks International Association, Local 1111 including conferences, receptions, meetings, rallies, portraits, and the opening of a Pilot Medical Center in June 1958. A small amount of ephemera includes a 1939 souvenir program from the Retail Bakery Clerks Union Local 1111, and certificates. Materials date from the late-1930s to the late-1970s.
  The Retail Clerks International Association, Local 1111, formerly the Retail Bakery Clerks union, Local 1111, began in 1935 and was led in its early years by Abe Moglin, president Al Kugler, and Secretary Treasurer Lillian Hecht.
  - [Retail Clerks International Association Local 1111] [Includes Souvenir Program], circa 1939, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Retail Clerks International Association, Apr 1950, 1965, undated (Box Shared Tamiment OS002)
  - Retail Clerks International Association Local 1111 [1 of 4], 1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Retail Clerks International Association Local 1111 [2 of 4], circa 1950-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Retail Clerks International Association Local 1111 [Includes Letter from White House] [3 of 4], circa 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Retail Clerks International Association Local 1111 [Includes 3 Certificates] [4 of 4], circa 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - RCIA 1111, circa 1939, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - RCIA 1111 - Abe Moglin, Mar 5, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Oversize Convention Photographs, 1968, undated
  This series consists of two panoramic group photographs, from the RCIA Inaugural, dated September 28, 1968, and from a UFCW convention, possibly in the late-1980s or 1990s.
  - RCIA and UFCW Convention Photographs, 1968, undated (Flat-file 7, Drawer 15)
  - Convention Photograph Mounted on Wood, undated (Box 2)
  - Convention photos, 1960-1983 (Box Shared Tamiment 032)